Register of the Kyril Drenikoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1958-1983 (Boxes 44-52)
  - "L'emprise soviétique sur la Bulgarie,", 1981 (Folder 50: 55)
  - "Iuli Rozental," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1981 (Folder 50: 56)
  - "Kiril Peichinovich," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1981 (Folder 50: 57)
  - "Magda Petkanova," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1981 (Folder 50: 58)
  - "La mamille royale de Bulgarie,", 1981 (Folder 50: 59)
  - "Marko Tsepenkov," Makedonska tribuna ('Obrazi' column), 1981 (Folder 50: 60)
  - "Ungaria I bulgarskoto natsionalno vozrazhdane," Makedonska tribuna, 1981 (Folder 50: 61)
  - "Soviet Ascendancy on Bulgaria," speech, 14th World Anti-Communist League Conference, Taipei, 1981 August (Folder 50: 62)
  - Bibliografi'i'a za Makedoni'i'a, 1982 (Box-folder 51: 1-4)
    Background material and typescript
  - Bibliografi'i'a za Makedoni'i'a, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 1-4)
  - Speech, 1982 (Folder 52: 5)
  - "Autopsy of a Satellization," 15th World Anti-Communist League Conference, Tokyo, Japan, 1982 December (Folder 52: 6)
    Typescript. Includes typescript of French version "Autopsie d'une satellisation"
  - "Un peintre oublié,", 1983 (Folder 52: 7)
  - Speech, 1983 (Folder 52: 8)
  - Speech, 1983 February 26 (Folder 52: 9)
  - Speech relating to Croatian independence, 1983 April 9 (Folder 52: 10)
- ANTI-BOLSHEVIK BLOCK OF NATIONS (ABN) FILE, 1961-1983 (Boxes 53-55)
  Bulletins, clippings, commemorative book, conference file, correspondence, leaflets, open letter, and press releases, related to activities of the ABL and arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General (Folder 53: 1)
  - Bulletins, 1972-1983 (Folder 53: 2)
  - Clippings (Folder 53: 3)
  - Commemorative book for the 30th anniversary, 1973-1983 (Folder 53: 4)
  - Conference file
    - 1961 (Folder 53: 5)
    - 1964 (Folder 53: 6)
    - 1965 (Folder 53: 7)
    - 1968 (Folder 53: 8)
    - 1969 (Folder 53: 9)
    - 1970 (Folder 53: 10)
    - 1971 (Folder 53: 11)
    - 1972 (Folder 53: 12)
    - 1973 (Folder 53: 13-14)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - 1975 (Folder >54: 2)
    - 1976 (Folder 54: 3)
    - 1981 (Folder 54: 4)
    - 1982 (Folder 54: 5-6)
    - 1983 (Folder 54: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1983 (Box-folder 55: 1-2)
  - Leaflets (Folder 55: 3)
  - Open letter to Richard Nixon, 1972 December 26 (Folder 55: 4)
  - Press release, undated (Folder 55: 5)
- WORLD ANTI-COMMUNIST LEAGUE (WACL) FILE, 1968-1983 (Boxes 55-63)
  Clippings, conference file, correspondence, press releases, and miscellany related to activities of the WACL, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General (Folder 55: 6)
  - Clippings (Folder 55: 7)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - Conference file
    - 4th:: Kyoto-Tokyo, Japan, 1970 (Folder 56: 2)
    - 5th:: Manila, Philippines, 1971 (Folder 56: 3-4)
    - 6th:: Mexico City, Mexico, 1972 (Folder 56: 5-6)
    - 6th:: Mexico City, Mexico, 1972 (Box-folder 57: 1-3)
    - 7th:: London, Great Britain, 1973 (Folder 57: 4-6)
    - 7th [sic]:: Washington, D.C., United States, 1974 (Folder 57: 7)
    - 7th [sic]:: Washington, D.C., United States, 1974 (Box-folder 58: 1-3)
    - 8th:: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1975 (Folder 58: 4-6)
    - 9th:: Seoul, Korea, 1976 (Folder 58: 7)
    - 9th:: Seoul, Korea, 1976 (Box-folder 59: 1-5)
    - 10th:: Taipei, Republic of China, 1977 (Folder 59: 6-7)
    - 10th:: Taipei, Republic of China, 1977 (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - 11th:: Washington, D.C., United States, 1978 (Folder 60: 2-3)
    - 12th:: Asunción, Paraguay, 1979 (Folder 60: 4)
    - 13th:: Geneva, Switzerland, 1980 (Folder 60: 5)
    - 13th:: Geneva, Switzerland, 1980 (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - 14th:: Taipei, Republic of China, 1981 (Folder 61: 2-4)
    - 15th:: Tokyo, Japan, 1982 (Folder 61: 5)
    - 15th:: Tokyo, Japan, 1982 (Box-folder 62: 1-2)
    - 16th:: Luxemburg, Luxemburg, 1983 (Folder 62: 3-5)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Folder 62: 6)
    - General (Box-folder 63: 1)
    - Ku, Cheng-kang (Folder 63: 2-3)
    - Labin, Suzanne (Folder 63: 4)
  - Press releases from the Foreign Affairs Circle (British chapter of WACL between and ) on the activity of the WACL, 1970 1973 1983 (Folder 63: 5)
  - Miscellany (Folder 63: 6)
- LIGUE BULGARE DES DROITS DE L'HOMME FILE, 1948-1983 (Boxes 63-64)
  Annual report, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, membership cards, open letters, press releases, statutes, and miscellany related to activities of the League, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    - General, 1948-1979 (Folder 63: 7-8)
    - Executive Bureau, 1979-1980 (Folder 63: 9-10)
    - Garnevski, Andrei, 1972-1979 (Folder 63: 11)
      Includes correspondence with Kyril Drenikoff
  - Annual report, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Bulletins, 1975-1983 (Folder 64: 2)
  - Clippings (Folder 64: 3)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1978-1980 (Folder 64: 4)
    - Fédération Internationale des Droits de l'Homme, 1978-1980 (Folder 64: 5)
  - Membership cards
    - General (Folder 64: 6-7)
      Includes addresses
    - World Federation members (Folder 64: 8)
  - Open letters, 1969-1980 (Folder 64: 9)
  - Press releases, 1972 (Folder 64: 10)
  - Statutes (Folder 64: 11)
  - Miscellany (Folder 64: 12)
- INFORMATIONS BULGARES FILE, 1968-1983 (Box 65)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Afrique Asie, 1983 (Folder 65: 1)
  - Cahiers d'études cathares, 1968 (Folder 65: 2)
  - Centre d'Etudes de Politique Etrangère, 1968 (Folder 65: 3)
  - Moulis, Adelin, 1968 (Folder 65: 4)
  - Tajan, Jacques, 1973 (Folder 65: 5)
- INSTITUT CULTUREL BULGARE FILE, 1958-1976 (Boxes 65-67)
  Correspondence and documentation on the publication Edin Zavet, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Correspondence
    - Bibliothèque de Documentation Internationale Contemporaine (Folder 65: 6)
    - Hague Academy of International Law (Folder 65: 7)
  - Publications - Edin Zavet
    - General
      - 1958-1959 (Folder 65: 8-11)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 66: 1-3)
      - 1960-1961 (Folder 66: 4-6)
    - Articles and fragments (unpublished) (Folder 66: 7)
    - Articles and fragments (unpublished) (Box-folder 67: 1-2)
    - Lists of contributors and subscribers (Folder 67: 3)
- CENTRE DE RECHERCHES ET DE DOCUMENTATION BALKANIQUE FILE, 1971-1983 (Boxes 67-69)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent, and financial records.
  - General (Folder 67: 4)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Folder 67: 5)
    - Academia Republicii Socialiste Romania, Bucharest, 1976-1982 (Folder 67: 6)
    - Académie Macédonienne des Sciences et des Arts, Skopje, 1975-1976 (Folder 67: 7)
    - Albertini, G. (Centre d'Archives et de Documentation Politiques et Sociales), 1975 (Folder 67: 8)
    - L'alternative, Paris, undated (Folder 67: 9)
    - Archivo General de Indias, Sevilla, 1973 (Folder 67: 10)
    - Atlantic Institute, Paris, 1973 (Folder 67: 11)
    - Bibliothèque de Documentation Internationale Contemporaine, Paris, 1967-1983 (Folder 67: 12)
    - Buchhandlung Dialog, Frankfurt, 1976 (Folder 67: 13)
    - Bulgarisches Forschungsinstitut in Österreich, Vienna, 1981-1982 (Folder 67: 14)
    - Bulgarska Torgovo-Promyshlena Palata, Sofia, 1974 (Folder 67: 15)
    - Bund der Vertriebenen, Bonn, 1980 (Folder 67: 16)
    - Les cahiers du samizdat (Meeûs, Anthony de), 1977 (Folder 67: 17)
    - Chrisroff, Nancy, 1974 (Folder 67: 18)
    - Commission Internationale de Juristes, Genève, 1973 (Box-folder 68: 1)
    - Communauté de Secours aux Églises Martyres (CSEM), 1981 (Folder 68: 2)
    - Le Courrier de la liberté, Munich, 1975-1980 (Folder 68: 3)
    - Cyril and Methodius National Library, Sofia, 1971-1983 (Folder 68: 4-7)
    - Derzhavno Arkhivno Upravlenie, Sofia, 1971-1978 (Folder 68: 8)
    - E. J. Brill Leiden, Editeur et Imprimeur, Paris, 1976 (Folder 68: 9)
    - Editorial Juventud, Barcelona, 1977 (Folder 68: 10)
    - Grain de blé, 1981 (Folder 68: 11)
    - Hemus (Foreign Trade Organization for Import and Export of Literature, Works of Fine Arts and Culture), 1972-1983 (Folder 68: 12)
    - Italy. Camera dei Deputati, Rome, 1974 (Folder 68: 13)
    - Italy. Ministero degli Affari Esteri. Commissione per la Pubblicazione dei Documenti Diplomatici, 1976 (Folder 68: 14)
    - Ivanov, P. ( Zora), 1982 (Folder 68: 15)
    - Janson, Charles ( Soviet Analyst), 1978 (Folder 68: 16)
    - Lashermes, Maurice, 1971 (Folder 68: 17)
    - Martinus Nijhoff (Booksellers and Subscription Agents), 1983 (Folder 68: 18)
    - Missi, Paris, 1982 (Folder 68: 19)
    - Rafailov, Rafael (Graficas Sorima), 1982 (Folder 68: 20)
    - Rühle-Diebener-Verlag, Stuttgart, 1973 (Folder 68: 21)
    - Service Orthodoxe de Presse et d'Information, Paris, 1982 (Folder 68: 22)
    - Simidžioski, Slobodan, 1980-1982 (Folder 68: 23)
    - Sofia Press Agency, Sofia, 1983 (Folder 68: 24)
    - Soiuz na Bulgarskite Khudozhnitsi, Sofia, 1981-1982 (Folder 68: 25)
    - Tsentralna Biblioteka pri Bulgarska Akademia na Naukite, Sofia, 1973-1983 (Folder 69: 1)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1976 (Folder 69: 2)
    - Variorum (John Smedley), London, 1982 (Folder 69: 3)
    - Velikoternovski Universitet Kiryl i Methodii, Veliko Ternovo, 1973-1976 (Folder 69: 4)
  - Financial records (Folder 69: 5)
  - Guest book (Folder 69: 6)
- BORIS III, CZAR OF BULGARIA FILE, 1937-1983 (Box 69)
  Broadcast, edict on military spending, proclamation, script of movie about Boris III, and subject file, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General (Folder 69: 7)
  - Broadcast on the 40th anniversary of his death (Radio Free Europe), 1983 (Folder 69: 8)
  - Edict on military spending, 1939 March (Folder 69: 9)
  - Proclamation, 1937 June 17 (Folder 69: 10)
  - Script of movie about Boris III, entitled "A Legacy." (Folder 69: 11)
    See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Noronha da Costa, Marcus and Storia illustrata
    Includes correspondence with King Simeon regarding his part in the movie (draft speech included), 1967.
  - Subject file - Joanna, queen consort of Boris, Czar of Bulgaria, 1953-1983 (Folder 69: 12-14)
- SIMEON II, KING OF BULGARIA FILE, 1952-1975 (Boxes 70-74)
  Announcements, biographies, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, declaration, draft reform plan, list, message, stationery, and subject file, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Invitations and BORIS III, CZAR OF BULGARIA FILE/Script of movie.
  - Announcements, 1964-1965 (Folder 70: 1)
  - Appeal to the Bulgarian people, 1975 (Folder 70: 2)
  - Biographies
    - General (Folder 70: 3)
    - V sluzhba na Rodinata, 1965 (Folder 70: 4)
    - Al servicio de su patria, 1969 (Folder 70: 5)
  - Bulletin issued by His Majesty's Chancellery, entitled Mesechen osvedomotelen biuletin na kantselariiata na Negovo Velichestvo Tsaria, 1962-1967 (Folder 70: 6-8)
    Loose and bound issues. One volume includes announcements, biographies, cards, clippings, correspondence, invitations, and family tree
  - Bulletin issued by His Majesty's Chancellery, entitled Mesechen osvedomotelen biuletin na kantselariiata na Negovo Velichestvo Tsaria, 1962-1967 (Boxes 71-72)
  - Bulletin issued by His Majesty's Chancellery, entitled Mesechen osvedomotelen biuletin na kantselariiata na Negovo Velichestvo Tsaria, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 73: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1964 (Folder 73: 3)
    See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Simeon II, King of Bulgaria
  - Declaration on the 25th anniversary of the Communist regime in Bulgaria, 1969 August (Folder 73: 4)
  - Draft reform plan for the new Bulgarian state presented to Simeon II by G. Dobrudzhanski, 1958 (Folder 73: 5)
  - List of paintings in the Royal Palace in Madrid (Folder 73: 6)
  - Message on the tenth anniversary of the Constantian Society, 1980 (Folder 73: 7)
  - Stationery (Folder 73: 8)
  - Subject file
    - Celebrations
      - 18th birthday, 1955 (Folder 74: 1)
        Includes proclamation to the Bulgarian people
      - 19th birthday, 1956 (Folder 74: 2)
      - 28th birthday and 10th anniversary of his majority, 1965 (Folder 74: 3)
      - 25th anniversary of his accession to the throne, 1968 (Folder 74: 4)
    - Marriage, 1962 January 20 (Folder 74: 5-6)
      Lists of guests and gifts received
- SUBJECT FILE, 1879-1983 (Boxes 75-145)
  Accounts, appeals, broadcasts, certificates, correspondence, declarations, lists, notes, memoranda, petitions, press releases, reports, resolutions, statutes, surveys, treaties, clippings and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abraxas (Folder 75: 1)
  - Accademia del Mediterraneo, 1974-1978 (Folder 75: 2)
  - Académie Européenne de Sciences Politiques, 1972-1973 (Folder 75: 3)
  - Académie Internationale D'Héraldique, 1967 (Folder 75: 4)
  - ACP (African, Caribbean and Pacific Countries), 1983 (Folder 75: 5)
  - African countries (Folder 75: 6-7)
  - Agriculture - Economic aspects (Folder 75: 8)
  - Albania (Folder 75: 9)
  - Aleksandur I, Prince of Bulgaria, 1857-1893 - Death (Folder 75: 10)
  - Alet (France) (Folder 75: 11)
  - Algeria (Folder 75: 12)
  - American-Bulgarian Eastern Orthodox Church (Folder 75: 13-16)
    Includes articles, report, petition, statutes
  - American-Bulgarian Good Neighbor League (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - American Bulgarian League, 1951-1958 (Folder 76: 2-3)
  - American Council for World Freedom, 1976 (Folder 76: 4)
  - Americano-Bulgarska Liga za Soedinenite Amerikanski Shtaty i Kanada, 1965 (Folder 76: 5)
  - Amicale "Dimitre Guitchev" des Réfugiés Agrariens Bulgares en France, 1961 November (Folder 76: 6)
  - Amitiés Belgo-Chinoises, 1982-1983 (Folder 76: 7-8)
    Includes some biographies
  - Amnesty International (Folder 76: 9)
  - Anarkhisticheska Grupa, Sofia, 1911 (Folder 76: 10)
  - Annuaire National des Lettres, 1973 (Folder 76: 11)
  - Anticommunism, 1974 (Folder 76: 12)
  - Anti-Communist International, 1975 (Folder 76: 13)
  - Anti-Communist movements - Bulgaria, 1975-1977 (Folder 76: 14-15)
  - Anti-fascist movements, 1974 (Folder 76: 16)
  - Arab countries (Folder 76: 17)
  - Archeology - Bulgaria (Folder 77: 1)
  - Architecture - Bulgaria (Folder 77: 2)
  - Archivo Genealogico, Madrid, 1980-1981 (Folder 77: 3)
  - Art, Bulgarian, 1940-1942 (Folder 77: 4)
  - Asia (Folder 77: 5-6)
  - Assassinations - Bulgaria
    See Communist trials - Bulgaria
  - Assemblée Internationale d'Enfants (Drapeau de la Paix), Sofia, 1979 August 15-25 (Folder 77: 7)
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations (ACEN) (Folder 77: 8-10)
    Appeals, correspondence, declaration, memoranda, plans, press releases, reports, resolutions, speeches, surveys
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations (ACEN) (Box-folder 78: 1-3)
  - Associatio Sanctus Benedictus Patronus Europae, 1980-1981 (Folder 78: 4)
  - Association Belgo-Hispanique, 1980-1981 (Folder 78: 5)
  - Association Belgo Sud-Africaine (A.B.S.A.), 1983 (Folder 78: 6)
  - Association des Hautes Etudes Internationales, 1966-1968 (Folder 78: 7)
  - Association Générale des Etudiants de l'Institut Catholique (Folder 78: 8)
  - Association "Les Amis du Théâtre Royal Parc," Brussels, 1982 (Folder 78: 9)
  - Association of Confessional Lutheran Seminaries, 1983 (Folder 78: 10)
  - Association pour le Développement des Echanges Linguistiques et Culturels entre la France et les Pays de l'Europe Orientale (ELCEFEO), 1977-1979 (Folder 78: 11)
  - Association pour les Etudes et Recherches Historiques, 1959-1971 (Box-folder 79: 1-2)
  - Associazione degli Intellettuali Rifugiati in Italia, (A.I.R.I.), 1953 (Folder 79: 3)
  - Associazione Italia-Bulgaria, Rome (Folder 79: 4-7)
    Includes writings and translations into Italian from Bulgarian, plays, poems, etc. by Luigi Salvini, 1954-1957
  - Associazione Italiana degli Accademici del Mediterraneo, 1962 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Associazione Italiana per i Rapporti Culturali con la Bulgaria, 1959 (Folder 80: 2)
  - Associazione Monarchica Italo-Bulgara, 1968-1970 (Folder 80: 3)
  - Astoul, Eugène (Frère Imbert-Stanislas), 1980-1981 (Folder 80: 4)
  - Australia (Folder 80: 5)
  - Balkan countries (Folder 80: 6-7)
  - Balkan Peninsula - Civilization - Byzantine influence (Folder 80: 8)
  - Balkan Peninsula - History - War of 1912-1913 (Folder 80: 9)
  - Balkanski, D. V., 1968 (Folder 80: 10)
  - Baltic Committee in Scandinavia, 1973 (Folder 80: 11)
  - Baltic countries
    See Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe
  - Bankov, Pastor, 1982 (Folder 80: 12)
  - Basques. Letter to the editor from Guy M. Héraud (Folder 80: 13)
  - BBC (Folder 80: 14)
  - Becker, Robert Charles (Folder 80: 15)
  - Bekoff, Nadji (Folder 80: 16)
    Album illustrated with photographs
  - Belgisch Helsinki Komitee, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Bertecic, Josip, 1969 (Folder 81: 2)
  - Biafra (Folder 81: 3-4)
    See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Dimitroff, Ivan
    Memoranda, reports and correspondence with M. T. Mbu (Chairman, Public Services Commission, Government of the Republic of Biafra) and the Ministère de la Marine of Belgium regarding Kyril Drenikoff's involvement in the sale of torpedo boats, armaments, and equipment to Biafra.
  - Boev, B. (Folder 81: 5)
  - Bogoridi, Stephan, 1909 (Folder 81: 6)
  - Bonnefous, Edouard M., 1968-1971 (Folder 81: 7)
  - Bosco, Giovanni, Saint, 1916 (Folder 81: 8)
  - Boukoff, Jouri (Folder 81: 9)
  - Brazilian Society for the Defense of Tradition, Family and Property, 1964-1978 (Folder 81: 10)
  - British League for European Freedom, 1973-1974 (Folder 81: 11)
  - British League of Rights, 1974-1981 (Folder 81: 12)
  - Bulgaria
    - General (Folder 81: 13)
    - General (Box-folder 82: 1-6)
    - Armed Forces (Box-folder 83: 1-4)
    - Armed Forces (Box-folder 84: 1-5)
    - Civilization. Material related to the Bulgarian cultural week in Frankfurt at Main, 1942 (Box-folder 85: 1-2)
      Includes Bulgarian proverbs translated into German that may have been exhibited in Frankfurt
    - Commerce (Folder 85: 3-4)
    - Economic conditions (Folder 85: 5-7)
      See also: Gabenski, Ivanko
    - Economic conditions (Box-folder 86: 1-3)
    - Foreign relations
      - General (Folder 86: 4-8)
        Includes treaty with the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, the United States of America, Australia, the Belorussian Soviet Socialist Republic, Czechoslovakia, Greece, India, New Zealand, the Ukrainian Soviet Socialist Republic, the Union of South Africa, and the People's Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, 1947. Also includes appendices, memoranda, reports, 1946-1948
      - Serbia. Treaty, 1912 February 29 (Box-folder 87: 1)
      - Turkey (Folder 87: 2)
        Includes offical documents in Arabic
    - History
      See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Gorazd, Archimandrite
      - General (Folder 87: 3-15)
      - General (Box-folder 88: 1-5)
      - General (Box-folder 89: 1-4)
      - Uprising, - Exhibit organized by the Deutsche Liga fũr Menschenrechte, 1923 (June) (Folder 89: 5)
    - Politics and government
      - General (Folder 89: 6-7)
      - General (Box-folder 90: 1)
      - Bulgarian national organizations, 1965 (Folder 90: 2-4)
      - Kermektchiev, Alexandre G., Le premier pas dans la vie politique des Bulgares, 1905 (Folder 90: 5)
      - Prime ministers of Bulgaria, 1879-1944 (Folder 90: 6)
    - Population (Folder 90: 7)
    - Religion (Box-folder 91: 1-5)
    - Religion (Box-folder 92: 1-4)
    - Social conditions (Box-folder 93: 1)
      See also: Soviet Union/Social conditions
      Includes memoir by unidentified author.
    - Miscellany (Folder 93: 2-8)
  - Bulgaria. Consulstvo (Berlin) (Box-folder 94: 1)
    Visitors book
  - Bulgaria. Legatsia (France), 1956-1959 (Folder 94: 2)
  - Bulgaria. Ministerstvo na Venshnite Raboti i na Izpovedaniata, 1910 (Folder 94: 3)
  - Bulgaria. Ministerstvo na Vutreshnite Raboti, 1953-1971 (Folder 94: 4)
  - Bulgaria. Ministur na Voinata, 1923-1930 (Folder 94: 5)
  - Bulgaria. Narodnoto Sobranie, 1965-1977 (Folder 94: 6-7)
  - Bulgarian Academy of Science, 1959-1978 (Folder 94: 8)
  - Bulgarian Academy of Science, 1959-1978 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - Bulgarian British Review, 1929 (Folder 95: 2)
  - Bulgarian Communist Party (Folder 95: 3-4)
  - Bulgarian Communist Party (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - Bulgarian Escapee Program of Church World Service, New York, 1955 (Folder 96: 2)
  - Bulgarian literature (Folder 96: 3-9)
  - Bulgarian music (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - Bulgarian National Agrarian Union, 1982-1983 (Folder 97: 2)
  - Bulgarian National Committee "Free and Independent Bulgaria,", 1967-1972 (Folder 97: 3)
  - Bulgarian National Front, 1965-1984 (Folder 97: 4-6)
  - Bulgarian Olympic Committee, 1980 (Folder 97: 7)
  - Bulgarian Social Center of America, 1977 (Folder 97: 8)
  - Bulgarians
    - Italy
      See Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari, Rome
    - North and South America, 1980-1981 (Folder 97: 9)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 97: 10)
  - Bulgarska Liga za Pravata na Choveka (Folder 97: 11)
  - Bulgarska pravoslavna tzerkvo (Bulgarian Orthodox Church), 1956-1976 (Box-folder 98: 1-4)
  - Bulgarska Sotsialisticheska Partia, 1977 (Folder 98: 5)
  - Bulgarski Demokraticheski Sgovor (Folder 98: 6)
  - Bulgarski Natsionalen Front v Amerika i Kanada, New York, 1959 (Folder 98: 7)
  - Bulgarski Natsionalen Komitet, 1965-1967 (Folder 98: 8)
  - Bulgarski Taen Natsionalen Komitet, 1913 (Folder 98: 9)
  - Bulgarski Zemedielski Naroden Soiuz, 1978 (Folder 98: 10-11)
  - Bulgarskia Komitet za Podpomagane na Bezhantsite Bulgari Namitashchi se v Italia, Gertsia i Turtsia, 1949-1950 (Folder 98: 12-13)
  - Bulgarskia Komitet za Podpomagane na Bezhantsite Bulgari Namitashchi se v Italia, Gertsia i Turtsia, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
  - Bulgarsko Osvoboditelno Dvizhenie (Bulgarian Liberation Movement), 1973-1976 (Folder 99: 3)
  - Byelorussian Liberation Front, 1971-1976 (Folder 99: 4)
  - Canetti, Elias (Folder 99: 5)
  - Catholic Church (Folder 99: 6-11)
  - Catholic Church (Box-folder 100: 1-2)
  - Central America (Folder 100: 3)
  - Centre Culturel Sun Yat-sen, 1981-1983 (Folder 100: 4)
  - Centre for International Studies Limited, 1982 (Folder 100: 5)
  - Centro di Studi Storici e Politici della Reale Casa di Bulgaria, 1975-1982 (Folder 100: 6)
  - Chaffanjon, Arnaud, 1968-1970 (Folder 100: 7)
  - Charms and amulets (Folder 100: 8)
  - Chevènement, Jean-Pierre, 1976-1978 (Folder 100: 9)
  - China
    - General (Folder 100: 10)
    - Foreign public opinion, Belgian
      See Human rights/China
  - Choublier, Max M., 1934 (Folder 100: 11)
  - Civil rights and socialism, 1969-1977 (Folder 100: 12)
  - Civil rights and socialism, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 101: 1-3)
  - Cliquet, René, 1983 (Folder 101: 4)
    Includes statutes of the Fondation René Cliquet
  - Collège Gevenol, 1983 (Folder 101: 5)
  - Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari, Rome (Folder 101: 6-7)
    Includes lists of Bulgarians in Italy and abroad
  - Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari, Rome (Box-folder 102: 1-4)
  - Comitato per l'Amicizia e i Rapporti Culturali con la Bulgaria (Folder 102: 5)
    See also: Società Italo-Bulgara
    Clippings and lists relating to an exhibit in Sofia on Italian publishing, 1956.
  - Commission for Technical Cooperation in Africa South of the Sahara, 1960-1961 (Folder 102: 6)
  - Commission Internationale de Juristes, Brussels, 1957-1964 (Folder 102: 7-8)
  - Communication and traffic - Bulgaria, 1962-1969 (Folder 102: 9-12)
  - Communism
    - General (Folder 103: 1-3)
      Includes issues of Il comunismo nel mundo, 1959-1962
    - Bulgaria (Folder 103: 4)
    - Eastern Europe, 1975-1979 (Folder 103: 5-6)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 103: 7)
  - Communist trials - Bulgaria (Folder 103: 8)
    Includes lists of people sentenced to death
  - Communist trials - Bulgaria (Box-folder 104: 1-2)
  - Concert tours
    - Bulgaria (Folder 104: 3)
    - Italy